When you find yourself in a less resilient mindset,
there's some good news.
Research shows that mindsets are malleable.
Not only can you change your mindset over time,
you can even shift them in the short term.
One way to have your mindset shifted is priming.
For example, there are experiments in which students about to take an exam
were shown either intelligence words or neutral random words.
You can guess that the students primed on intelligence
statistically achieved better results on their exam.
This is why inspiring quotes, morning mantras, and other
self-priming techniques can be so effective.
But there are times you need something more powerful
and pointed to shift your mindset.
This is where the APR technique can help.
The basic idea is that you bring awareness to your current mindset
and realize how it affects your behavior,
pause to create a wedge in which you can
choose to do something differently,
take on a different lens, so to speak,
and use specific reflection questions to reframe
your mindset into one that serves you better.
This in turn will help you respond through your behavior,
emotions and thoughts in a way you desire.
This technique is very helpful in the moment.
It's also helpful for the long term.
The continual practice of APR can help change any entrenched mindsets
that have become the default from years of repetition and reinforcement.
Now let's practice.